# Rachid Riad | Curriculum Vitae

31 rue de l'Abbe Groult – 75015 Paris – France > +33 666522141 • > riadrachid3@gmail.com > https://rachine.github.io

My current area of research is Health Behavior Informatics via Speech analysis. The goal is to build technologies to support clinical practice during diagnosis and treatment of the Huntington disease.

### **Education**

ENS - Paris Saclay Cachan

Master of Science, Machine Learning and Computer Vision, with Honours 2016–2017 Courses: Object recognition and Computer Vision, Modelization in Neuroscience, Numerical Imaging, Reinforcement Learning, Graphs in Machine Learning, Convex Optimisation, 3D points and modelization, Online Learning

Ponts Paristech Paris

Engineering degree, Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, 2013–2017 Computer Science (C++, Python), Spectral Analysis, Operational Research, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Financial mathematics, Optimization

### Lycée Pierre de Fermat

**Toulouse** 

Preparatory class for the highly competitive entrance exams to the Grandes Écoles, 2011–2013 Intensive preparation in Math and Physics

#### Master thesis

Title: Discovery of linguistic units from acoustic speech and multi-modal views

Supervisor: Emmanuel Dupoux

**Description**:

- o Developing a system for unsupervised discovery of Words and Phoneme units.
- o Participation in the Zero Resource Challenge.
- o Participation in the JSALT workshop

### **Experience**

Research....

# Laboratoire de Science Cognitive et Psycholinguistique, ENS

Paris

Research Intern

April 2017-October 2017

Discovery of linguistic units from acoustic speech and multi-modal views

### Carnegie Mellon University's Language Technologies Institute

Pittsburgh

Summer Research Intern

June 2017-August 2017

2017 Jelinek Summer Workshop on Speech and Language Technology, Rosetta Stone project,

### **CERMICS** applied Mathematics laboratory Ponts Paristech

Paris

Research Intern April 2014–August 2014

Study of financial Mathematics model

Industry.....

Mapjam San Francisco, USA

Geo Software Engineer intern

October 2015-August 2016

o Building GIS Stack and complex mapping applications.

o Map design cartography.

o 500 start-ups accelerator program

Vehicle Data Science Oakland, USA

Software Engineer intern September 2015–October 2015

o Data visualisation with D3.js and Leaflet.js

**Bouygues Construction** 

Paris. France

Blue-Collar intern September 2013 – October 2013

o Blue-collar work on a construction site

Languages

French: Native

English: Highly proficient in spoken and written

Spanish: Good working knowledge

Computer skills

**Programming Languages**: Python, C++, bash **Machine Learning**: Theano, Dynet, Sklearn

Web development: HTML/CSS, JavaScript Visualisation: D3.js, Leaflet.js, Praat, Audacity

Databases: SQL, Postgres/Postgis, OS: Linux, Docker

**Hobbies** 

Basketball: Team Captain and practice of Basketball at regional level for 10 years

Soccer: Member of the Ponts Alumni Soccer Team

## Community service

- Organisation of the career fair of three of the best engineering schools in France: this career fair hosts 3000 participants and has a 700k€turnover.
- o I have been part of the team elected at Ecole des Ponts to represent the students. I have organised the farewell trip for my school for 200 people, managing a 15-person team with a budget of 20k€.

### References

| Industry  | Academia                                 |
|---|--|
| <ul> <li>Scollay Petry CEO of Mapjam</li> </ul>         | Pr. Bernard Lapeyre                      |
| <ul> <li>JD Margulici CTO of Infinite Uptime</li> </ul> | <ul> <li>Pr. Frederic Meunier</li> </ul> |